Dadada, please do not buy this ICICI
plan.  [laughter]
Absolutely right, you have to listen to the child.
Why is the child refusing this ULIP plan
?  Let's quickly try to find it
out.  Because this plan says that it is
market linked, unit linked, it is an
insurance plan and it has life cover.  Will pay your
premium and save tax.  bl bl bl
two in one three in one four in one five
and different acronyms and synonyms are given.
But let me help you understand that
if you go to its website of ICICI Pro
and you will try to understand this plan, then
you will enter that I want to
invest Rs. 1 lakh every year for
the next 10 years, then you will enter that
my policy term should be 20 years in
which you are paying premium for 10 years, then you will also
choose a fund, so
you have chosen a safe fund,
chose a conservative fund, whether it is in equity, which is
your ICICI Blue Chip
Fund or ICICI Large Cap Fund,
I will call that, as they have given here,
they have shown only five year returns.
Like those five year returns will be
applicable over the 20 years, that is
not possible.  The returns of 10 years itself become
different.  But let's assume for now.
Let's go by these
numbers that the five year returns are 17.1%
returns.  And after that, if we take this plan then
your maturity benefit comes out
to be close to 1.14 CR.  Seeing this you will
feel like wow I am doing a great
justice to what I am paying and
maybe my child will also benefit from it, the same
is shown in advertisements also but
if I take this in an Excel file, in the
Excel file let's quickly try
to see the numbers that I am taking
ICICI Proof Smart Asor Plan in which
my 11047 every year and that 1047
is added because of the accidental
death rider thing that if by mistake an accident happens
and there is a death which happens.
So your kid does not travel.  So you pay that
extra ₹1000 every year.  Woh Aap Pay Karne
Rahoge 10 Saal And At Maturity
Taking Into Consideration The 17.1% [Music]
Returns
Promised By The ICICI Bluechip And Large
Cap Fund Your Overall IRR Returns Come Out
To Be 16.2%
Only.  Ok?  Now you will say that these are very
good returns.  Why am I saying only in this
?  I am saying only
because your life cover in this is
only ₹1 lakh.  Just think, is your life
worth just ₹1 lakh?  That is why I say
that these two in one, three in one, four in one
, five in one are bull shut things.  You should always have these
things separate.  Never ever should I say
combine investment with
insurance, investment with life cover,
investment with anything else.  So
what have I done?  A simple example has been taken of
ICICI Bluechip Fund plus Term Insurance
because first of all you are being fooled
that you will get 17.1% returns.
If you see, actually ICICI's Bluechip and Large Cap Fund has given you returns of 21 plus annually. If you look at five years, then
their allocation charges and
fund management charges are already very
high.  There are bl bl things.  Let's not go
into details.  So that is actually 21%
something.  So if you
take a direct plan in normal ICICI Bluechip Fund and
invest ₹1 lakh for 10 years and leave it, then
after 20 years it becomes 2.44 CR, just
imagine 1.3 CR extra, which means
it will become more than double.  And I am giving you
a term insurance of one CR.  Your life
cover is not ₹1 lakh Your life cover is ₹1 crore
Which can be in the name of your child or children In
case something unfortunate happens For that
you are paying ₹15000 Every year you
know you pay and you know For the next 20
years then also your overall return comes out
to be 20.56% This
tells you a very simple answer that this
policy is a waste of your time and money Go
ahead and purchase the policy separately Make a
wise choice for your kid Thank you
[Sangeet]